Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Individual songs in English by title, 1.
  - When Santa Had the Rheumatiz
    Words by Willlis N. Bugbee, music by Thos. B. Weaver. Copyright 1921 by Willis N. Bugbee. A sticker for Baker's Plays, Boston, has been pasted over original publisher name.
  - Which Witch Doctor (Did You See)
    Words and music by Nick Venet and John Neel, arranged by Chris Langdon. New York: Karen Music Inc., 1958. Published by Edwin H. Morris & Co., Ltd., London. Recorded by the Mudlarks on Columbia Records.
  - The Whooping Cough Germs
    Words by Lida Keck-Wiggins, music by Thos. B. Weaver. Copyright 1923 by L. M. Paine. A sticker for Baker's Plays, Boston has been pasted over the original publisher name. Song for children with directions for staging.
  - Why Winnie Went to War to Be a Nurse
    Words and music by Joseph McManus, Jr. Published by the McManus Publishing Company, Los Angeles, 1915. World War I nursing. Puchased 2017 and added to the collection.
  - Wildwood Weed
    Words and music by Jim Stafford and Don Bowman. Copyright 1964 by Famous Music Corporation, Boo Music and Parody Publishing Co. Recorded by Jim Stafford on MGM Records. On hallucinogenic weeds on the farm.
  - Witch Doctor
    By Ross Bagdasarian. Chicago: Monarch Music Co., c. 1958. Recorded by David Seville on Liberty records.
  - The Woman in White
    No information on creators. Minneapolis: The Pillsbury Flour Mills Company, c. 1939. "As featured by Donna Lee in the popular radio program, 'The Woman in White.'" On the nurse.
  - The Wonderful Pill
    Cover and first page of music only. Words by Oswald Allan, music by Benjamin Barrow. London: Charles Sheard, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.).
  - X-Ray Waltzes
    Composed by Harry L. Tyler. Corning, N.Y.: I. N. Easterbrook. Copyright 1896 by the Corning Music Co. Cover image of a man's hand under an X-Ray tube.
  - The Yeast Foamers March
    Composed by J. Oliver Riehl. Chicago: Northwestern Yeast Company. Copyright 1929 by the National Broadcasting Company. "Composed for and played by The Yeast Foamers Novelty Orchestra on the Northwestern Yeast Company Radio Programs through the National Broadcasting Company Network." Advertisements for "The Yeast Foam Family" on the back cover.
  - You 'Ave to 'Ave 'Em
    Words and music by Charles Osborne, arranged by Henry E. Pether. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1897 in USA. Sung by Harry Randall. Two verses on germs and medicines.
  - You Can't Hear Angels, Billy
    Words and music by Pond and Harrison. London: Charles Sheard & Co., c. 1900 in USA. A kindly doctor comes in and stands by the homeless boy's hospital bed.
  - You Can't Make Love With A Cold
    Words and music by Gene Crowley. London: Peter Maurice Music Co., Ltd, c. 1951. Recorded by Phil Harris. His romantic life is spoiled by sneezing, coughing, the flu, and hay fever.
  - You'll Never Need a Doctor No More
    By Chris Smith. New York: Skidmore Music Co., c. 1921. Sung by Bert Williams in "Broadway Brevities." Blackface characters on cover.
  - Young America: March
    By Bert Brown. Troy, N.Y.: Koninsky Music Co., c. 1918. Cover shows a child in a Red Cross uniform and a boy dressed as a soldier. If needed, they will fight in the future like their parents did in World War I.
  - You're a Sweet Little Headache
    Words and music by Leo Robin and Ralph Rainger. New York: Paramount Music Corporation, c. 1938. From "Paris Honeymoon," a Paramount Picture, with Bing Crosby.
  - You've Got to Stop It
    Words by Andrew B. Sterling, music by Felix Bernard. New York: Tell Taylor, c. 1915. The doctor tells the young woman to stop dancing all evening.
  - You're My Big Fever
    Words and music by John J. Schneider. Philadelphia: Songtext Music Company, c. 1934. "Fox Trot Novelty Song."
- Individual Songs in French by title, 2.
  Many of the French songs are comic pieces performed at theaters in Paris including the Eldorado, the Alcazar, the Amabassadeurs, and La Scala. Many items contain both spoken words and music. Some are monologues, either with music for the entry and exit of the performer, or no music at all. A number of the songs feature the clyster, a huge enema syringe, or its updated version the "Clyso" pump.
  - Large format, mostly 19th century (Box 8)
    There are a few small-format songs in this subseries. The arrangement of the collector was maintained.
    - Agitez (Box 8)
      Words by Th. Aillaud, music by Félix Chaudoir. This item is a leaf from a issue of Paris qui Chante, published by Chavat and Girier, Paris, July 22, 1903. Paris qui Chante was published weekly beginning in 1903. Sung by Max Morel.
    - L'Alchimiste: quadrille pour le piano
      Title page only. No music. Composed by Alph[on]se Longueville. Paris: Ménestrel, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Allopathe et homeopathe: duo
      Words by "GIL," music by F. Boissière. Printed by Delanchy, n.d. (19th cent.). Cover has been trimmed, although the music is complete.
    - L'Anglaise malade
      Cover and first page of music only. Words and music by Paul de Lock. Paris: chez Canaux, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by Levassor at the Théatre de Variétés.
    - La Ballade du pharmacien
      By Faure (?). Song published in Le Potard Enchainé, humor supplement to La Gazette des Pharmacies, Paris, August 1921. The four pages of the issue contain articles and cartoons about pharmacists and pharmacies.
    - Ça jette un froid: chansonette comique
      Words by G. Dorfeuil, music by Ch. Porny. Paris: Ph. Feuchot, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Ce cher docteur
      Words and music by Edmond Lhuillier. Paris: Eug. Mathieu, n.d. (19th cent.). Cover illustration by Cham (Amédée de Noé, 1818-1879). Spoken words on a separate sheet pasted in. Performed by A. Des Roseaux.
    - C'est l'radium
      Music by Eug. Lemercier, words by F. Pradines. Published in Paris qui Chante, July 3, 1904. On Pierre and Marie Curie and the discovery of radium. Sung by Mayol.
    - Chanson sans calcium
      Words by J. C. Massoulier, music by M. Blanchot. Paris: Editions musicales Septentrion, c. 1966. Sung by les Freres Jacques.
    - Le Charlatan, ou le remède universel
      Cover and first page of music only. Words by Mr. Paulin, music by Charles Plantade. Paris: Frey, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Crispino e la comare: polka
      Cover page only. No music. Composed by Desgranges. Paris: Léon Escudier, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Une Cure extraordinaire: trio saynète
      Words by Ernest Reuxel, music by Ch. Pourny. Paris: Cartereau, n.d. (19th cent,). Spoken and sung by there women.
    - La Dent à Jean Maclou
      Words and music by Frédéric Bérat. Paris: Schonenberger, n.d. (19th cent.). Contains spoken words as well as music.
    - Le Dernier chant du menestrel
      Incomplete. Only one page of music. Words by H. T. Poisson, music by A. Romagnesi. Paris: A. Romagnesi, n.d. (19th cent.). Image on reverse of music is of a doctor and patient. The singer is dying despite the medical oracle of Epidaurus.
    - Le Docteur Isambart
      Arranged by L. Bousquet. Brussels: J. E. Libau, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by L. Bousquet as the "doctor."
    - Le Docteur Puff
      Words by Ernest Bourget, music by Edmond Lhuillier. No publication information possibly because page has been trimmed. Contains spoken words as well as music. Performed by Berthelier at the Théâtre du Palais Royal.
    - Le Docteur Puff
      Larger format version of the previous item. Words by Ernest Bourget, music by Edmond Lhuillier. Paris: Columbier, n.d. (19th cent.). Performed by Berthelier as the "doctor" at the Théâtre du Palais Royale.
    - Le Docteur Mirobolan
      Cover page only. By Araban. Comic opera by E. Gautier. Paris: E. Gérard et Cie., n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Le Fantassin malade, ou les lieux qui m'ont vu naître
      Words by Ch. M. Delange, music by Auguste Olivier. Paris: [publisher illegible], n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Les Herboristes: chanson metiéorologique
      Words by Louis Capet and E. Carel, music by Robert Planquette. Paris: Maison L. Bathlot, n.d. (19th cent.). Contains spoken words as well as music. Performed by Paulus at the Eldorado.
    - L'Homoéopathie, ou les malices de la médecine
      Words and music by Hippolyte Maignand. Paris: N. Pate, n.d. (19th cent.). Comic scene produced by Lefevre.
    - L'Homme universel
      Words by Etienne Tréfeu, music by A. Thys. Paris: Ménestrel, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Il faut souffrir pour être beau!
      Words by F. De Courcy, music by L. Clapisson. Paris: J. Meissonnier fils, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - I'Incomparable Mirobolanpouff!: parade charlatanesque
      Lithograph for a song cover by "Stop" (Louis Pierre Gabriel Bernard Morel, Retz, 1825-1899) from the Journal Amusant, No. 116, March 20, 1858, p. 6. On the same page, also by "Stop," is a lithograph for "Le Père Sabremioche," showing an old man with a wooden leg and crutch.
    - Je n'bois que d'leau d'pulna: chansonette comique
      Cover page and one page of music only. Words by A. Bruneau, music by A. Massage. Paris: L. Bathlot, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by Mr. Réval at the "Gd. Concert Parisien."
    - Je sens que l'homme j' m' enrhume du cerveau
      Words by Armand des Roseaux, music by Maximilien Graziani. Paris: Alphonse Leduc, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by A. des Roseaux.
    - Je vous conseill' pas d'fourrer vot' nez la d'dans: Chansonette comique
      Words by A. Philibert, music by C. Pourney. Paris: A. Philibert, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by J. Perrin at the Eldorado. One verse is on an infirmary staff member at Val de Grace Hospital who carries out the doctor's orders. Image of an enema syringe on the cover.
    - Le Jeune malade: romance de Millevoye
      Cover and first page of music only. By Roux-Martin. Copyright by the author. Sold at music stores in Paris and Lyon.
    - Le Lavement au bouillon gras, ou la peur d'être cocu
      Cover only. "Récit par Villemer." Paris: Bassereau, n.d. (19th cent.) Image of a giant enema syringe on the cover.
    - La Marche des microbes
      Composed by Eug. Carion. No information on publisher. Late 19th cent. Dedicated to Dr. Arnoldy.
    - La Marchande d'esprit: ronde charlatanesque
      Words and music by L. Durbec. Paris: Le Bailly, publisher -- O. Bornemann, successor, n.d. (19th cent.). A girl promotes a liquor.
    - Le Médecin et le dieu d'amour
      Words by François Charles Simonin, music by J. B. Wekerlin. Paris: Ménestral, n.d. (19th cent.). A comparison of characteristics of Cupid and the doctor.
    - Méfiais vous d' la poume' de terre!
      Title page and first page of music only. Words by E. Bourget, music by J. J. Hormille. Paris: Cotelle, n.d. (19th cent.). Image shows potatoes as humans, one carrying an enema syringe. Sung by Mr. Levassor at the Théâtre du Palais Royal.
    - La Métempsycose, ou observations sur ce système
      Cover only. No music. By Jaime and Ch. Plantade. Paris: Alexandre Cotelle, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Mon dieu laissez-moi vivre encore
      Cover illustration and first page of music only. Words by Auguste Richomme, music by J. M. Cambon. Paris: A. Petit, n.d. (19th cent.). Image of a sick woman seated.
    - Un Monsieur sourd
      Words by Ernest Martial, music by Eugène Poncin. Paris: Société Anonyme du Nouveau Répertoire de Concerts de Paris, n.d. (19th cent.). Spoken words as well as music.
    - La Mort de Paul Bert
      Words by Henry Moreau, music by J. Henri. Paris: F. Bigot, ca. 1886. Paul Bert (1833-1886), a student of Claude Bernard, was a French physiologist. The cover image refers to his appointment by the government as resident-general at Tonkin in 1886.
    - Ne plaisantons pas avec ces chos's la
      Cover only. No music. Words by E. Durafour, music by F. Barbier. Paris: L. Vieillot, n.d. (19th cent.). One vignette shows a woman giving a can of leeches to a another woman in bed. An enema syringe and medicines are on the table.
    - Les Pastilles Géraudel
      Words and music by Jules Jouy and Gerny. Leaf from Le Courrier Français, December 26, 1886. Sung by Sulbac at the Eldorado.
    - Le Pharmacien: chansonette
      Cover and first page of music only. Words by Tarride, music by Georges Charton. Paris: F. Brondert, n.d. (late 19th cent.). Sung by Kam-Hill at the Eldorado and Georges Charton at the Trianon.
    - Pitié pour ma binette: lamentation comique
      Words and music by Joseph Arnaud. Paris: Arsène Goubert, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by the author at the Alacazar.
    - Polichinelle
      Words and music by Pauline Thys. Paris: Ménestrel, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - La Poudre de Perlinpinpin: scène comique avec parlé pour cinq personnages
      Cover and one page of music only. Words by Marie Vernet, music by Georges Meugé. Paris: Chartereau, n.d. (19th cent.). Image of a woman promoting a powder to an audience of four other women,
    - Les Profiteurs-bienfaiteurs
      Words by Dominique Bonnaud. Old tune arranged by Adolph Stanislaus. Published in La Baïonnette, March 30, 1916, About a salesman/inventor claiming to benefit soldiers. One verse is on health products. Two copies.
    - Les Remèdes les plus simples sont les meilleurs: Scène comique
      Words by R. F. Boutin, music by Adolph Vaillard. Paris: Nadaud, n.d. (19th cent.). Spoken words as well as music. Performed by Mr. Levassor.
    - La Revision
      Words by F. Dupuy and Maader, music by P. Bourges. Paris: Voiry, n.d. (19th cent.). In part on the medical examination of military recruits.
    - Le Rhumatisant
      Words by Delormel and Garnier, music by P. Pierret. Published in Paris qui Chant, August 7, 1904.
    - Seigneur ayez pitié de mon enfant
      Cover only. No music. Words by L. L., music by Emile Steinküler. Paris: S. Lévy, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Si jeunesse savait! Si vieillesse pouvait!
      Words and music by Edmond Lhuillier. Paris: Columbier, n.d. (19th cent.). Image of a father suffering from gout and his son.
    - Les Singes savants: Quadrille pour piano
      Composed by Auguste Spèïneer. Paris: Alex[and]dre Grus aîné, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Soeur Mélanie
      Words by Madame La Comtesse Olympe M. de Lernay, music by A. De Villebichot. Paris: Ménestrel, n.d. (19th cent.). Image of a nun by the bedside of a wounded soldier.
    - Soigner-vous!
      Words by Ch. Blondelet and Ct. Saclé, music by Ch. Pourny. Paris: Ph. Feuchot, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by Mr. Velly at the Eldorado.
    - Le Soldat mourant et la Soeur de Charité
      Cover and one page of music only. Words by Lenoir Maunoir, music by Gel. Prieur Duperray. Paris: S. Richault, n.d. (19th cent.).
    - Tout par amour
      Words by J. Montini, music by O'Kelly. Paris: J. Meissonnier fils, n.d. (19th cent.). Nurse and wounded soldier.
  - Small format, 19th century - 1971 (Box 9)
    These items -- sheet music and comic monologues -- were formerly housed in looseleaf notebooks separate from the songs in the previous subseries. Sizes vary but all fit into 28.5 x 22 cm sleeves. Most date from the late 19th to the early 20th century. There are some small-format songs in the large-format subseries.
    - Adieu Madame Curie
      Recitation. Words by Jean Lygo and Jacques Francis. Paris: Editions Lyjo, c. 1934. Performed by Lyjo, Jacques Francis, and others. 1934 was the year of Marie Curie's death.
    - Les Adieux de Lise
      Words by Arthur Canu and Henri Canu, music by Ch. Niepce de St Victor. Paris: L. Colas, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Debailleul at the XIXe Siècle, by Sarius at La Scala, by Sautereau at the Orphéum, and by Mme. Delacroix at the Gaité Montparnasse.
    - L'Ambulancière, ou soldats, cessez le feu - romance patriotique
      Words by Lucien Cologne, music by Emile Spencer. Paris: F. Bigot, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Mr. Albin at the Eden-Concert and by Mlle. Bernier at La Scala. Cover shows a Red Cross nurse bandaging a soldier on the battlefield, but she herself has been hit and is bleeding.
    - Amour et rhumatisme
      Words by Emile André, music by Robert Planquette. Paris: L. Bathlot-Joubert Editeurs, n.d. Cover shows a woman rubbing the unclothed back of a man.
    - Anatomie du conscrit
      Words by Eugène Rimbault, music by Emile Spencer. Paris: Repertoire Polin, n.d. Performed by Polin at La Scala. Cover shows an officer looking at a naked recruit.
    - L'Apothicaire de la rue du Caire: grande scène comique
      Words by Léon Laroche, music by Ch. Pourny. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Delpierre at the Concert Parisien.
    - L'Aspirine: samba comprimée
      Words and music by Marc Fontenoy. Paris: Editions Paul Beuscher-Arpège, c. 1953.
    - Aspirine et Pyramidon
      Words by Hector Barreyre, music by S. S. Nannelli. Paris: La Parisienne, Edition Musicale, n.d. Performed by Cadex at the Européen. Also sung by Danvers, Max Lucian, Berki, Duc Paul, Romanet, Doublé, and others.
    - La Belle Bourbonnaise/ La Nouvelle Bourbonnaise
      Music arranged by M. H. Colet. Drawings by M. Trimolet, engravings by Couché and Torlet. No information on publication. Mid-19th century.
    - Bergers et bergères
      By Francine and Xavier Privas. Song appears to be extracted from Nos Chansons Françaises, no year, pp. 240-241.
    - Blouse de dentiste (Blues)
      Words by Boris Vian, music by Henri Salvador. Paris: Editions Musicales Patricia et Société d'Editions Musicales Internationales (S.E.M.I.), c. 1958.
    - Bon remède!
      By G. Choquet de Broca. No publication information. Extracted from a songbook.
    - Le Bouillon de la Capitaine
      Words by Villemar-Delormel, music by Emile Duhem. Paris: Emile Benoit, n.d. Performed by Duhem at the Alcazar d'Eté. Image of a man in an apron carrying a huge clyster (enema syringe).
    - Le Bulletin de Santé
      Words and music by Georges Brassens. Paris: Editions Musicales, c. 1966. Recorded by George Brassens on "Philips."
    - Ça suffit à mon bonheur
      Words by Emile Carré, music by Abel Queille. Paris: Ph. Feuchot, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Performed by J. Arnaud at La Scala. Cover shows a man getting out of bed and a servant ready with a clyster.
    - Ça vaut mieux...que attraper la scarlatine
      Words by André Hornez, music by Paul Misraki. Copyright 1936 by Ray Ventura & Cie. & Royalty, Paris. "One Step de l'Opérette 'Normandie'."
    - Le Cas de Pitou
      Words by R. de St. Prest and L. Christian, music by Albert Petit. Paris: A. Queille, Editeur-Compositeur, n.d. Image of a comic man, and off to his side is a hand pointing a clyster at him.
    - Le Cataplasme: chansonnette comique
      Words by René Bastien, music by D. Grimonpont. Extract from Nos Chansons Françaises, No. 108, 1929. Incomplete.
    - Le Charlatan, ou le remède universel
      Words by Mr. Paulin, music by Charles Plantade. Paris: Frey, Editeur, n.d. (early 19th century). Lithograph on cover of a man in Napoleonic costume standing in a carriage and promoting a remedy. Three musicians in the carriage are playing and a crowd gathers round.
    - Le Charlatan
      Words by E. Hubert, music by F. Boissière. Paris: Fouquet, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Lithograph of a man standing on a table and promoting a bottle to a crowd. Behind him is a drum.
    - Le Charlatan: scène comique
      Words by E. Barlie, music by L. Godefroy. Paris: Smyth, Editeur, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Music and spoken words.
    - Le Charlatan Arabe
      Words by Baltha and L. Guetteville, music by L. Gueteville. Paris: Repertoire Gueteville, Plébins, Editeur. This is a comic scene with spoken words as well as song. Performed by Pascal at the Concert Parisien, and by Chambot at the Eldorado. Accompanied by a separate brochure with the words to the scene as performed by Chambot. The cover image shows an Arab wearing a tassled hat and holding out a remedy in a bottle.
    - Chez le pharmacien
      By Bach and Henry-Laverne. Paris: E. Bousquet, Editeur, n.d. (20th cent.). Recorded on Odéon records. This a comic scene with words and no music. Henry-Laverne plays the pharmacist and Bach the client.
    - Chez le pharmacien
      By Bach and Henry-Laverne. Another version of the above comic scene, published in Receuil de cinq dialogues et scènes comiques célebres créées et enregistrés sur disques "Odeon" par Bach et Henri-Laverne. Paris: Les Editions Jean Picot, Ex-Editions Sait Gilles, n.d. (early 20th cent.).
    - Chirurgie esthétique
      Monologue by Eugène Wyl, in Recueil de dix monologues et chansons loufoques créées par Pierre Dac. No. 51 Paris: Les Editions Jean Picot, Ex-Editions Saint-Gilles, n.d. [early 20th century].
    - Le Clou de ma belle-mère
      Words by Disle, music by A. Teste. Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. (19th cent.). Color image of a grandmother suddenly struck with an ailment while at a dining table with her family.
    - Le Clyso: chanson refraîchissante
      Words and music by E. Bousquat, Ch. Gonzalez and M. Labastrou. Paris: A la Chanson Moderne, n.d. Image of a pump-like device identified by the next item as a "clysopompe," a modern version of the clyster.
    - Le Clysopompe
      Monologue by Mac-Nab. Extract from Poèmes incongrus by Léon Vanier. In Les Chansons illustrées, No. 18, n.d. Perfomed by Mac-Nab. Image of the pump.
    - Consultation
      Monologue by Xanrof. From Les Chansons Illustrées, No. 86, 2e série (No. 142 de la Collection), Libraire Contemporaine, Paris, n.d. (20th cent.). Entire issue.
    - Cours de chimie
      Words by Briollet-Alain, music by H. Christiné. Paris: M. Labbé, Editeur, n.d. (early 20th cent.). Music and spoken words. Performed by Dranem at the Eldorado and by René Raoult at the Petit Casino.
    - Les Corbeaux: chansonnette
      By Léon Maillot. Verses but no music. Paris: A. Fouquet, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Riviore at the Horloge. On the Catholic clergy which become crows as they head toward Rome. The complicated image includes a man with a clyster as a weapon.
    - C'que l'médecin m'a dit: chansonnette
      Words by Eug Rimbault, music by P. Codini. Extracted from an unidentified source. Performed by Polin.
    - Les Deux médecins: saynète comique
      Words by A. Isch Wall, music by Emile Duhem. Paris: O Bornemann, n.d. Comic dialogue with some music about a quarrel between two doctors.
    - Le Docteur Louftingue
      Words by Plébus and Rodor, music by Fernand Heintz. Paris: "Ancienne Maison Guéprotte & Bloch - Madame Cécile Gilbert, Successeur," n.d. (20th cent.). From "Edition Musicale 'Au Point d'Orgue'." A monologue performed by Constantin as the "doctor."
    - Le Docteur Isambart
      Words by Joseph Kelm, music by Vicomte de Flaboss. Paris: Marcel Labbé, Editeur, n.d. Performed by Joseph Kelm as a charlatan promoting a remedy. There is an earlier version of this song in the large format French songs.
    - Le Docteur Zanzibar
      Words by Maader and Dupuy, music by Guéteville and Maader. Originally published by Guéteville, Paris. From Les Chansons et Monologues Illustrées, No. 471, n.d. Words only.
    - La Doctoresse
      Words by Yody, music by L. Demortreux. Paris: A La Gamme, n.d. (late 19th cent.). In the color image, an attractive woman doctor feels the pulse of a gentleman. There is a fetus in a bottle on the table.
    - Le Doigt de pied de Saint Guignolet: monologue comique
      Monologue by Delormel and Garnier. Paris: Eveillard et Jacquot, Editeurs, n.d. Performed by Réval at La Scala. Cover image of patients showing an ailing part of their bodies to the toes of a statue of a Catholic saint.
    - Les Elèves en médicine
      Words by Jean Bonin, music by Emile Duhem, Paris: Emile Benoit, Editeur, n.d. Color image of men and women promenading in the street.
    - Elixir Lagane: chanson des coutteux